So it might seem absurd to do this calculation of the standard deviation.
قد يبدو إجراء هذه العملية الحسابية للانحراف المعياري أمرًا غريبًا.
I mean, it's such a complicated way to measure the spread
أعني، إنها طريقة معقّدة لقياس انتشار
of our data compared to the five number summary we saw earlier.
بياناتنا مقارنة بملخص العدد خمسة الذي رأيناه مسبقًا.
But it turns out that the standard deviation is used all the
لكن يتضح أن الانحراف المعياري يُستخدم دومًا
time to get a single number to compare the spread of two data sets.
للحصول على عدد واحد مقارنة بانتشار مجموعتي بيانات.
It is kind of nice to be able to talk about how spread out our data are from one
من الجيد أن تكونوا قادرين على التحدّث عن كيف يتم انتشار البيانات من
another without having to report an entire table of values.
مجموعة إلى أخرى دون الحاجة إلى الإبلاغ عن جدول القيم بالكامل.
We can just compare the standard deviation for
لا يمكننا سوى مقارنة الانحراف المعياري
one group to the standard deviation of another group.
لمجموعة واحدة بالانحراف المعياري لمجموعة أخرى فقط.
And we have a way to tell which dataset is more spread out.
لدينا طريقة لتحديد أي مجموعة بيانات هي الأكثر انتشارًا.
Having one number simplifies the amount of
إنّ وجود عدد واحد يُبسّط كمية
information that the person you're reporting to needs to consume.
المعلومات التي يحتاج الشخص الذي أبلغتم عنه إلى استهلاكها.
Having the single value also has
إنّ وجود قيمة واحدة أيضًا له
other advantages with regard to what is known as inferential statistics,
ميزة أخرى من حيث ما يُعرف باسم الإحصائيات الاستنتاجية،
but that's beyond what we need to know now.
لكن هذا يتجاوز ما نحتاج إلى معرفته حاليًا.
For now, we just need to know that we have a way to take all of
في الوقت الحالي، نحتاج فقط إلى معرفة أن لدينا طريقة لأخذ جميع
our values and get a single number
قيمنا والحصول على عدد واحد
that tells us how spread out they are from one another.
يُحدد لنا كيف يتم الانتشار من مجموعة إلى أخرى.